anytrip.com 2016-06-23

# Privacy & Cookie Information - HostelBookers

#### Hostelbookers.com Privacy and Security Statement

Hostelworld.com Limited (“ **Hostelworld** ”) operates the Hostelbookers.com website, mobile site and mobile app (together the “ **Hostelbookers Sites** ”). This privacy statement sets out our privacy and security practices and forms part of the Terms and Conditions that apply to your use of the Hostelbookers Sites. 

Hostelworld has been processing online hostel reservations since 1999 and we have always placed the security of our internet transactions and our customers’ credit card details as our top priority. We will continue to offer our customers the highest level of security available for online transactions and hope this reassures you when you make your reservations with us. 

Hostelworld realises that some people are unsure about entering their personal details into websites and apps over the Internet. Below, we explain how we use your information and how we protect your privacy. Hostelworld and its associated companies respect and protect your right to privacy in relation to your interactions with the Hostelbookers Sites. Any information which is provided by you to Hostelworld via the Hostelbookers Sites or otherwise will be treated in accordance with the terms of the Irish Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 and/or such amending or replacement legislation as may be adopted in Ireland from time to time. 

#### Information Required To Process Your Booking

For us to process a booking for you on behalf of a travel services provider, we require some information from you. This includes your name, nationality, your gender (or the gender of the group you are in), your phone number and email address. Also, since we confirm your booking while you are on the Hostelbookers Site, we require your credit or debit card details so we can guarantee your beds when you pay your deposit. 

#### Who Sees Your Information

We are required to send your information to the travel services provider with which you booked travel services so that the travel service provider knows who you are and when you will use its travel services. We give your name, your nationality, your gender (or the gender of the group you are in), your phone number, your email address, your credit card details and of course, the details of your booking. The travel service provider requires this information to accept a confirmed booking from you. All travel service providers on whose behalf we facilitate bookings have agreed to the Hostelworld terms and conditions and accept this privacy policy. 

We may also pass your personal information to third party service providers who process it on our behalf in order to allow us to provide the best service to you. For example, we use various technologies provided by Google, including its Maps product and its analytics products, to enhance the Hostelbookers Sites. The following websites set out Google’s privacy policies in connection with these services <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/> and <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>. We only pass your personal information to trusted third party services providers in accordance with our obligations under the Irish Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. 

#### Security

All personal information exchanged between your device and the Hostelbookers Sites is encrypted using TLS. Our TLS Cert. is provided by GlobalSign. This ensures that your information is transmitted securely and is safe from third parties. 

You should be aware that where you link to another website from the Hostelbookers Sites, Hostelworld has no control over that other website. Accordingly, Hostelworld cannot guarantee that the controller of that website will respect your privacy in the same manner as Hostelworld. 

#### How We Use Your Information

In addition to the use and disclosure of information which is required when you avail of our travel related and data processing services (and which we describe above), we use your email address for sending you a confirmation of your bookings, pre-trip reminder e-mails, an email reminder to provide a guest review of your last accommodation stay, or occasionally to inform you of new features on the Hostelbookers Sites. Our booking confirmation and pre-trip reminder emails may contain banner advertising. We only use your phone number to contact you urgently if there is a problem with your booking. In circumstances where you contact us with a query, we use your contact details in order to respond to your query. 

Where you have given us your consent, we may send you emails that we think will be useful to you. This may include our regular e-newsletter, special offers, travel tips, customer surveys and information about products and services offered by us or our selected partners. Where your settings on your device permit us to send app notifications we may also send you app notifications containing similar information. You may opt out of receiving email messages at any time by clicking on the link provided in the email messages, and app notifications by changing the notification settings in your app. 

We take reasonable steps to ensure that your information is relevant to its intended use, and that it is accurate and up to date. As a registered Hostelbookers.com user, you can access and update your contact information, personal preferences and e-mail subscription choices at any time by visiting the account section of the Hostelbookers.com website. The information that you submit helps us to make your emails more useful, interesting and relevant to you. 

We use cookies and pixel tags on the Hostelbookers Sites and in our e-mails in accordance with our Cookies Policy, which is available here. 

On occasions, we may supply statistics about our customers to third-parties such as hostels or other agents. These statistics never contain personally identifying information. 

We would not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your prior consent. 

#### Targeted Advertising

We want to make it easy for you to take advantage of the travel related opportunities which we feature on the Hostelbookers Sites. We work with our advertising partners in order to try and ensure that when you see an advert for a Hostelworld brand it will be relevant to you and your interests. This applies to adverts that are displayed on Hostelworld’s own websites (including the Hostelbookers Sites, in Hostelbookers emails, and on websites owned by third parties). We do this by allowing our third party advertisers to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visit to the Hostelbookers Sites, such as the pages you visit on the Hostelbookers Sites and the locations you appear to be interested in. We also provide third party advertisers with non-personally identifiable information that we collect about you when you use the Hostelbookers Sites in order to only show you relevant adverts. We may also use such information in order to avoid showing you adverts on third party websites like Facebook and Twitter if we don’t think that you will be interested in them. 

When we share your information with third party advertisers we always ensure that we do so in compliance with our obligations under data protection law. We may use technologies such as “hashing” to ensure that we do not provide our third party service providers with your personal data. For more information on how our third party advertising service providers gather information about your use of the Hostelbookers Sites, please refer to our Cookies Policy which is available here. 

Some of our third party advertising partners ask us to make you aware of their privacy policies. These policies are available by following the links below: 

#### Reviews

We offer you the opportunity to post reviews of the accommodation you book through the Hostelbookers Sites. Where you provide us with a review, we may include your review on the Hostelbookers Sites and on selected partner sites. 

#### Website Testing

We use various technologies to allow us to test how the Hostelbookers Sites operate and allow us to improve our services. Further details of such tests are available at http://www.hostelbookers.com/website-testing/. 

#### Your Access And Amendment Rights

You have the right to request a copy of the information which we hold about you (for which we may charge you a small fee) and to have inaccuracies in the information corrected. If you wish to avail of any of these rights, please contact us at [customerservice@hostelbookers.com](mailto:customerservice@hostelbookers.com). 

#### Limitation And Exclusion Of Liability

Hostelworld, its directors, employees, servants and agents, affiliates or other representatives and their respective parent and subsidiary companies shall not be liable in respect of any claims, emergencies, demands, causes of action, damages, losses, expenses including without limitation, reasonable attorney fees and costs of proceedings arising out of or in connection with the use and/or dissemination of personal information relating to you in accordance with this privacy policy and your consent. 

#### Amendment Of Privacy And Security Statement

Hostelworld reserves the right in its sole discretion to amend this Privacy and Security Statement at any time and you should regularly check this privacy policy for any amendments. However, where any such amendments would materially change the use we make of any personal data, any such amendment will be subject to your prior consent.
